(upbeat music)
Welcome to our training on how to prevent
or resolve listing policy violations.
In this training, we'll share a number
of common listing violations
and our tips for resolving them.
We'll cover quality alerts and listing suppression,
duplicate ASINs, invalid GTINs,
prohibited and restricted products.
We'll also share how to access a list of errors
you might run into while listing products.
Let's get started.
You might receive alerts if you submit a product listing
that doesn't meet Amazon's requirements.
Your product could also become suppressed
from customer search results.
In certain cases, we won't add your listing
to the Amazon store.
This is to ensure customers don't encounter listings
with incorrect or missing information.
To check any listings of yours
that don't meet Amazon's requirements,
open the Seller Central main menu,
hover over inventory and select manage all inventory.
Filter the manage inventory page by a product status
like inactive, listing removed or search suppressed.
Or click search suppressed and inactive listings
to review and manage issues.
When you're ready to address a listing issue,
you can do so directly from the fix your products page.
Here are some examples of issues you can address
from this page.
You can add a missing core detail page requirement
like a product description or a compliant main image.
You can address out of stock SKUs
by updating the quantity or selecting restock.
Or you can review a potential duplicate.
If you determine the listings shown are not duplicates,
choose these are not duplicates to fix the issue.
Review the descriptions of each suppressed
or inactive listing.
Then take the necessary steps for resolution.
For a full walkthrough of the Fix Your products page
and how to address an issue,
watch the fix inactive or Suppressed listings video
in Seller University.
You may also experience blocked listings
which appear on the manage inventory page
with an inactive blocked status.
Next to that status, you'll notice either a red icon
or a yellow icon.
The red icon means the product can't be re-listed
while the yellow icon means it can.
Click the link next to the icon to learn more
and to correct any problems with the listing.
-
In the previous video in this series,
3.2 Prevent or Resolve product detail page policy violations.
You learned about product variations
and tips to remain compliant
with Amazon's variation guidelines.
Creating a new ASIN when a matching one already exists
in the Amazon store or incorrectly using variations
make product searching and purchasing decisions
difficult for customers.
Here's how you can check for potential ASIN duplicates.
Return to the same manage inventory page we just visited.
Then select potential duplicates.
If you don't see this option,
this means none of your listings have been search suppressed
due to potential duplicates.
Click review duplicates next to an ASIN
to review more details.
Then select the appropriate button to confirm
whether the ASIN is a duplicate.
You have 30 days from the date the ASIN first showed up
on this page to review and respond to potential duplicates.
Otherwise your ASIN will be suppressed from search results
and will no longer appear on this page.
If you find identical product detail pages,
you can request to merge them
using the self-service merge duplicate product
detail pages tool.
To access it, search merge duplicate product pages
in Seller Central and complete the requested fields.
-
Most products sold in the Amazon store
are required to have an industry standard product ID.
Product IDs are part of the GTIN system.
This universal system is used by Amazon
and across other marketplaces.
It's managed by an international organization
called Global Standards One or GS 1 for short.
GTINs ensure that products are uniquely identified
while being bought and sold
and also help sort and track items in transit.
Each GTIN pairs with a unique barcode
which makes product IDs scannable.
Depending on the product you're listing,
you might need to locate an existing GTIN,
obtain a new one or apply for an exemption.
In most cases, you'll need to provide a GTIN
when you create a new product detail page
in the Amazon store.
A GTIN is also the surest way to match your offer
to an existing product already sold in the Amazon store.
If you match a product using other information
like a brand or product name,
Amazon will automatically associate your offer
with the GTIN provided by the brand owner
or brand qualified seller who first listed the product.
There are a few cases in which a GTIN
isn't required to create a product detail page.
In those cases, you'll apply for a GTIN exemption instead.
This could occur if you're selling a private label
or handmade product for which the brand, manufacturer
or publisher doesn't provide a GTIN.
You might also apply for an exemption
if you're selling product parts or bundled products
in a single pack.
For more information on applying for an exemption
and creating a new product detail page
without a product ID,
complete the apply for a product ID
or GTIN exemption training in Seller university.
When you list the product in the Amazon store,
you may encounter an error stating you are using UPCs,
EANs, ISBNs, ASINs or JAN codes
that do not match the product you are trying to list.
We recommend taking the following steps to resolve the error.
One, check that the product information,
including the brand is properly recorded
on the GS1 database.
Two, ensure that the information included
in the GS1 database matches your listing exactly.
Differences in capitalization and punctuation
could result in a listing error.
Three, provide proof that the brand is affiliated
with the GTIN owner.
Valid forms of proof include a copyright, trademark,
legal agreement or a letter of affiliation.
After Amazon confirms that the product ID you provided
is valid, you can relist the product.
For more information about GTINs,
including requirements by product category,
search GTIN or product ID in Seller Central.
-
You've just learned that you'll need to confirm
a product is okay to sell before you list it.
It needs to be safe,
comply with all laws and regulations
and comply with Amazon's restricted product
and product compliance policies.
This helps ensure it isn't prohibited by Amazon
and meets all product-specific requirements.
You'll also need to determine
if the product requires any approvals.
Although products can be listed
in the Amazon store without approval,
we require that you apply to list certain products,
categories and brands enrolled in Amazon brand registry.
If you're just joining us in this series,
watch the 3.1 Apply to Sell a Restricted Product,
category or brand video in Seller University
for an in-depth walkthrough of apply to list
an existing product that requires category
or brand approval.
You can also search categories and products
that require approval in Seller Central
for more information.
While selling in the Amazon store,
you'll also need to assign the correct condition
to each product you list.
This helps ensure customers receive products
in the condition they expect,
an important part of a positive customer experience.
You can search condition guidelines
in Seller Central for more information.
We also recommend watching the Prevent Product
Condition Complaints video in Seller University
for tips on preventing and managing negative feedback
due to a product's condition.
-
As with violations,
you may encounter errors while listing products.
These errors can prevent your listing from being created.
In certain cases, the listing will be created,
but the error will cause it to be suppressed
from customer search results.
Because the Amazon store features products
sold by multiple sellers,
listing issues are commonly due
to incorrectly matching your products
to an existing listing.
Amazon uses product matching to eliminate duplicate listings,
meaning customers can browse by product
and use the product detail page
to make an informed buying decision.
Then they can choose to shop the featured offer
or continue navigating through offers from other sellers.
When you correctly match your product
to an existing listing,
you help customers find your offer.
You may encounter matching or conflicting errors
when you attempt to create a new product listing
or update an existing one.
These errors notify you about one of two issues.
Either the product ID or SKU you provided
may be assigned to a different product
in the Amazon store
than the one you're trying to list and sell.
Or the product ID you provided is associated
with one or more Asins,
but at least one product attribute you entered
doesn't match those Asins.
For example, imagine you correctly entered a product ID
that matches your product with the same item
in the Amazon catalog.
But when you created your offer,
you entered a brand, color, scent, size
or other attribute that doesn't match
what's already present for that particular Asin.
Amazon can't match your product IDs to existing Asins
unless the attributes you provide are identical to them.
Otherwise, we can't be sure
that the similar product we found in the Amazon catalog
is the same as the one you're trying to list.
Let's review your options
after receiving matching or conflicting errors.
You can often resolve them in one of three ways.
Confirming the product ID is correct.
Changing your listing's attributes
to match the existing product detail page
or replacing the product ID
with the Asin provided in the error message you received.
If you receive a matching or conflicting error,
you should first check that the product ID you provided
is correct and the product found in the Amazon store
is the same one you're trying to list.
The error message includes the product ID you provided
and the product we think it matches in the Amazon store.
A GTIN is also the surest way to match your offer
to an existing Amazon listing.
Note that you must always use a unique product identifier
obtained from the GS1 database.
Amazon uses this database to verify
that the product identifiers you and other sellers provide
are authentic.
Identifiers purchased from other websites won't be accepted.
If your product is different than the Asin
but the product ID you provided is correct
and was obtained from the GS1 database,
click request Amazon to update.
A pop-up window will appear
and describe the information you'll need to provide
about the discrepancy.
Amazon will analyze the information
and update the status of your request in your case log.
To review your case log, select help
in the top right corner of Seller Central.
Then click case log and locate the request ID.
If you've confirmed the product found in the Amazon catalog
is the same one you're trying to submit,
you can modify your product listing
to reflect the existing Asin's product detail page.
In certain cases you'll see an accept Amazon's value option
in the error message.
Select it and Amazon will process your submission.
If the error message doesn't include
the accept Amazon's value option,
refer to the error message you received
to find the correct attributes.
Or if you used an inventory file,
when you tried to create the listing,
you can find this information in your error report.
Make any necessary changes and then resubmit your listing.
Your product will display on the manage inventory page
in Seller Central.
As a reminder, you can get there by opening the main menu,
hovering over inventory and selecting manage all inventory.
If your product doesn't appear within 15 minutes
of resubmitting your listing,
select search suppressed and inactive listings
to return to the fix your products page
we reviewed earlier in this video.
Remember, you can search for the product,
review other listing issues,
and submit the required information from this page.
There may be instances when you've confirmed
the product found in the Amazon catalog
is the same one you're trying to submit.
But one or more attributes
on the existing ASIN's product detail page aren't correct.
After you list a product,
you may be able to suggest an edit
to a product detail page you share with other sellers
to help improve the page's accuracy.
Your ability to suggest an edit
depends on your relationship with the product.
If a product is part of a brand enrolled
in brand registry, only three types of sellers
can suggest edits.
The original rights owner who enrolled the brand,
other sellers verified as internal to the brand,
and resellers authorized by the brand.
If the product isn't part of a brand enrolled
in brand registry,
both the seller who created the product detail page
and all sellers who've matched offers can suggest edits.
To learn how to suggest edits,
complete the suggest an edit
to a product detail page training in Seller University.
-
If you're not eligible to suggest edits,
but would like to report an incorrect product detail page,
we recommend you contact seller support.
You may be asked to provide supporting materials
like manufacturer documents.
You may encounter other errors
while completing the listing process.
To learn more about an error,
search the word "error"
followed by the numerical code you received.
In this example, a seller received error 8571.
Reviewed its related help page
and learned that they've reached their ASIN creation limit.
To protect the on-site shopping experience for our customers,
we limit the number of listings,
both ASINs and offers you can create in a given week
until you establish a sales history with Amazon.
As you increase your sales, your capacity will increase.
We encourage you to prioritize the products you are listing
to increase your sales quickly.
If you're an established seller
and have created a high number of new listings,
we may temporarily remove your ability to create new listings.
We'll then re-evaluate your status on a weekly basis
until your listing privileges are reinstated.
-
This concludes our training on how to prevent
or resolve listing policy violations.
Continue to the next training to learn how to prevent
or resolve intellectual property or IP policy violations.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.
(
upbeat music)